A Winter Princess is a tv movie, romance film directed by Allan Harmon.
When Carly, secretly a princess, plans Snowden Peak’s Snow
Ball with Jesse, their attraction is undeniable.
In planning the event, the two make the gala a fundraiser to
help infuse much needed resources into the resort.
But without a celebrity draw, investors aren’t
interested, and Snowden Peak is put up for sale.
Will Carly allow her royal identity to be exposed to save the resort?
Carly / Princess Carlotta, played by Natalie Hall.
Jesse, played by Chris McNally.
Prince Gustav, played by Casey Manderson.
Prince Emile, played by Brendon Zub.
Allison, played by Lara Gilchrist.
King Kristof, played by Mackenzie Gray.
The Princess and the Frog is a 2009 American animated musical fantasy
comedy film produced by Walt Disney Animation Studios.
Inspired in part by the 2002 novel The Frog Princess by E.
Baker, the story is a modern adaptation of the German folk tale
"The Frog Prince" as collected by the Brothers Grimm.
The film was directed by John Musker and Ron Clements, and
written by Clements, Musker and Rob Edwards.
It stars the voices of Anika Noni Rose, Bruno Campos, Michael-Leon Wooley, Jim Cummings, Jennifer Cody,
John Goodman, Keith David, Peter Bartlett, Jenifer Lewis, Oprah Winfrey, and Terrence Howard.
Set in New Orleans during the 1920s, the film tells the story of a hardworking
waitress named Tiana who dreams of opening her own restaurant.
After kissing prince Naveen, who has been turned into a frog by the evil voodoo witch doctor Facilier, Tiana
becomes a frog as well and the two must find a way to turn human again before it is too late.
The Princess and the Frog began production in July 2006,
under the working title The Frog Princess.
It marked Disney's brief return to traditional animation, as it was the mainstream animation
studio's first traditionally animated film since Home on the Range (2004).
Musker and Clements, directors of Disney Animation's The Great Mouse Detective (1986), The Little Mermaid (1989), Aladdin
(1992), Hercules (1997), and Treasure Planet (2002) returned to Disney to direct The Princess and the Frog.
The studio returned to a Broadway musical-style format frequently used during the Disney Renaissance, and the film features a score and songs
composed and conducted by Randy Newman, well known for his musical involvement in Pixar films such as the Toy Story franchise.
The Princess and the Frog premiered at the Roy E.
Disney Animation Building on the Walt Disney Studios lot in Burbank on November 15, 2009, and first opened in a
limited release in New York City and Los Angeles on November 25, followed by a wide release on December 11.
The film received largely positive reviews from critics, who praised the return to a traditional hand-drawn animation style, though it was criticized for
its depiction of Louisiana Voodoo and alleged historical negationism of its depiction of the Southern United States during the Jim Crow era.
Although it underperformed by Disney's standards, it grossed $271 million and received
three Oscar nominations: Best Animated Feature and two for Best Original Song.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.